cruisemates.com 2006-06-17

# About CruiseMates.com

A guarantee of confidentiality concerning personal information conveyed by CruiseMates Readers.

* * *

CruiseMates will NEVER release your individual personal information without your consent. It is not required to register to enter CruiseMates but access to these features "Meet on Board," "Cruise Trivia," and the "Ship Poll" not be enabled. The CruiseMates registration process makes records of information we need in order to track your test scores and ship ratings, for example.

Importantly, registration for oue message boards is a completely separate record, and registering for either CruiseMates or CruiseMates message boards does not imply you are registered with both entities. You must register separately for the message boards. Click on the "Register" link on the main message board page.

To register with CruiseMates, we only require you to answer the following questions: 

> **
> * User Name:  
> 
> * Password  
> 
> * Email Address  
> 
> **
> * **ZIP code  
>  **
> * **Where did you hear about us?**   
> 

You create the user name and password. If a user name is already in use you will be asked to create a different name.

We also strongly REQUEST that you tell us additional information, such as your age, income, cruising history and cruising preferences -- you are NOT required to fill out this information. The information you submit voluntarily to our member registration is used to gather important statistics about the general demographics of our overall readership.

This optional information is solely to help create a better website through better understanding of who comprises our readership.

**Aggregate statistical information:**  
We may convey aggregated profile data regarding our members. This data DOES NOT contain personally identifying information such as name or email address. Individual identifying information will NEVER be provided to any of our advertisers or anyone else without your consent. However, aggregated data from our members may be shared with our partners. For example, we may let our advertisers know that approximately "X% of our members have cruised 5 times or more." However, we would never tell them anything about individual consumers (such as their name) unless the individual has given his/her consent to be contacted directly.

**Other uses of information:**  
As we state above, we will never sell, exchange, or release our members' individual identifying information (such as their name, email address or preferences data) to a third party without your consent. Occasionally, we might send data files containing personal information (such as email addresses) to third party agents for data processing services. These third parties are restricted from using this data in any way other than to provide services for us, and may not use or resell the data.

Unfortunately, CruiseMates cannot be responsible for any third parties who enter CruiseMates with the intention of gathering names and/or email addresses for the purposes of solicitation. If you should be solicited by anyone without your consent you can forward the solicitation to CruiseMates and we will look into the matter to see what if any action can be taken.

According to S.2326, Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 Websites must provide notice of its personal information collection and use practices; obtain parental consent for the collection, use, or disclosure of personal information from children aged 12 and under; provide parents access to their child's personal information; and establish and maintain reasonable procedures to ensure the confidentiality, security, accuracy, and integrity of personal information on children. CruiseMates supports and conforms with this pending legislation. The minimum age requirement to register with Cruisemates is 13. Any parents of children younger that 13 whose parents discover have registered with CruiseMates by lying about their age may contact us at [Editor](mailto:editor@cruisemates.com) to retrieve and delete the registration information of their children.

**How and When We May Contact You:**  
Cruisemates reserves the right to occasionally send its registered users email describing new articles, features or cruising opportunities offered by CruiseMates. You can opt out of these contacts completely, without giving up your right to remain a registered user of CruiseMates. See below for an explanation of how to do so.

We request that you give us as much contact information as possible, including mailing address and phone number, in case we ever need to contact you for an emergency situation. What if you won our cruise contest but had been deleting the emails because you thought they were spam? Wouldn't you appreciate a phone call?

**Recommend an Article:**  
If you use our recommendation service to email one of our articles to a friend, you will need to provide us with your friend's email address and your email address as a return address. CruiseMates will automatically send this person a one-time email, attaching the recommended article. We will also invite him or her to visit and register with our site. We will not use these email addresses for any other purpose.

**Security:**  
All the data you provide to Cruisemates is protected to ensure both its privacy and authenticity. Remember to keep your CruiseMates information private and secure; do not share your password with anyone!

**Cookies:**  
Cruisemates uses cookies when you register and login to CruiseMates. These cookies allow us to remember you as you visit pages in our site, so that you don't need to re-enter your password many times. These cookies do NOT track your movements in any other location other than the CruiseMates website. In addition, they do not register any personal information while tracking in CruiseMates. In other words, if your married but go to our singles cruising area, we will NOT be able to ascertain your individual identity.    More on Cookies?

**Newsletter Opt-in / Opt-out Policy:**  
If you wish to be a CruiseMates member but do not wish to receive any newsletter e-mailings about special features and offers, you can OPT-OUT of our mailing list by following the instructions contained in our newsletter. This is the only way to opt-out. It works, and it is private. If you have a problem opting out, please contact Customer Service.

We reserve the right to place advertising related information into our newsletter which you will see as a subscriber to our newsletter, but we promise to keep it to a minimum and always include "Opt-out" information with the newsletter. We may send out a "dedicated" email advertisement to companies that wish to contact people with an interest in cruising, but these emails will always contain opt out information.

**Updating Our Records:**  
Should we ever have the need to update our records, including those of people who have opted out of our newsletter subscription, we reserve the right to contact everyone who has ever registered with CruiseMates for the purposes of re-authentication of your subscription status at least once every two years. If you have no interest in hearing from us, please simply opt out of our email messages once again. Opting opt is simple and painless. 

**To change, update or correct User Profile:**  
Go to our "Help" area of cruisemates and look the words "How can I change my Personal Profile?" for the information on how to update your personal profile. If you have a problem please contact Customer Service. 

**Other Questions:**  
If you have other questions about CruiseMates or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at Customer Service.

* * *

More About CruiseMates - About Us.
